RALLAPALLI SOWJANYA

Mobile: +91 9381977036

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER rbnsowjanya567@gmail.com

Professional Summary

More than 8 years of experience in Development and Deployment of large-scale. Java, Java EE Applications.

Worked extensively on Java 2 Platform for developing Web and Distributed Applications by using JAVA, Java2EE (JDBC, JSP, Servlets), Oracle and XML technologies.

Experience in Open Source technologies like, Struts, Hibernate and IBM Sterling OMS.

Experience in using Adobe cq5 and Magnolia CMS Content Management System tools.

Experience in using Deployment process, CI/CD pipelines and Devops.

Knowledge and experience on Open Source technology like Spring MVC and Spring Boot.

Sound experience in Deploying applications using application servers like, Web logic, Jboss and Tomcat.

Good knowledge on RESTFUL web Services and SOAP based web services

Good Knowledge in integration and Regression testing.

Good implementation Knowledge on Micro Services, Jenkins, Git, Jira, Confluence.

Good working knowledge in XML and JSON

A very good Team player and enthusiastic with excellent inter-personnel skills.

A self-starter with excellent Communication, Interpersonal, and Analytical skills.

Worked in the following Domains: - Financial, Banking, and Insurance.

Technical Skills Summary:

O/S: MS Windows (95/98), Windows NT/XP, Windows 2000

Web Technologies: Java, JavaEE (JSP, Servlets, JDBC, XML), Struts, Spring, Spring Boot Hibernate, react js, Node js, Angular, Apache Ant, Log4j, Web-Services(Rest, SOAP)

Servers: Jboss Application Server 9.1/8.0, Web logic, Tomcat 6.x

Database: Oracle 8i/9i /10g

IDE: Eclipse 3.1, Net Beans, RAD, IBM Sterling OMS (Order Management System)
Tool, STS

Versioning Tools: CVS, SVN, Rational Clear Case.

Educational qualification

MCA (Master of Computers Application), Anna University, India

Professional Experience

Worked as a Senior Software Engineer at CBSI Bangalore from July 2022 to Jan 2024.

Worked as a Senior Software Engineer at HCL Technologies, Hyderabad from Nov 2013 - Oct 2019.

Worked as a Software Engineer at Kanha Tech Solutions Ltd, Bangalore from Aug 2012 - April 2013 date.

Project experience summary

Client

DCAW

Role

Senior Software Engineer

Duration

July'2022- Dec' 2023

Project Type

Development

DCAW is an advanced analytics platform that uses AI and ML to optimize data center operations by analyzing the data using ML models and providing predictive operational insights.

Roles and Responsibilities

Created and Verified API requests and REST protocols.

Involved in creating Dev Environment using web services.

Understanding of continuous integration of API automation scripts Involved in developing REST based applications.

Involved in deploying the API's in different environments using Jenkins.

Environment: Java 11, Spring Boot 2.7.13, Micro services, Restful Web services, Maria DB, Angular, Html.

Project experience summary

Client

HotTopic (HotTopic-US)

Role

Senior Software Engineer

Duration

Nov'2018- Oct'2019

Project Type

Development

HotTopic(stylized as HOT TOPIC) is a retail chain specializing in counterculture-related clothing and accessories, as well as licensed music. The stores are aimed towards an audience interested in rock music and video gaming, and most of their audience ranges from teens to young adults.

Approximately 40% of Hot Topic's revenue comes from sales of licensed band T-shirts. Hot Topic often negotiates exclusive licensing arrangements with musical artists, movie studios, and graphic artists. The majority of the stores are located in regional shopping malls.

Torrid is a clothing Retailer. Torrid LLC is an American women's retail chain formerly owned by Hot Topic. While it is still owned by Sycamore Partners, owners of Hot Topic, in 2015 the company branched off to become Torrid, LLC. The store offers plus-size clothing and accessories for women size 10-30. Torrid began operations in April 2001.[1] The first location opened in the Brea Mall in Brea, California. As of 2016, Torrid has over 400 stores in operation across 36 states in the United States. Torrid opened its first store location in Canada (Toronto) in August 2015.

Roles and Responsibilities

Involved in code coverage and sonarqube checks.

Involved in developing REST based applications.

Involved in deploying the API's in different environments using Jenkins.

Involved in documenting about the application on confluence pages.

Involved in code retrospective and grooming sessions.

Involved in developing the RAML and validating request against mule soft.

Environment: Java 8, spring boot, Micro services, Restful Web services, Oracle 10g

Client

Adobe Marketing Cloud (AMC) (McDonald's US)

Role

Senior Software Engineer

Duration

Aug'2017- Sep'2018

Project Type

Migration

Today, McDonald's is the world's largest restaurant chain, serving approximately 68 million customers daily in 119 countries across approximately 36,538 outlets. McDonald's primarily sells hamburgers, cheeseburgers, chicken products, French fries, wraps, breakfast items, soft drinks, milkshakes, and desserts. In response to changing consumer tastes, the company has expanded its menu to include salads, fish, wraps, smoothies and fruit. A McDonald's restaurant is operated by either a franchisee, an affiliate, or the corporation itself. The McDonald's Corporation revenues come from the rent, royalties, and fees paid by the franchisees, as well as sales in company-operated restaurants. According to a BBC report published in 2012, McDonald's is the world's second largest private employer (behind Wal-Mart with 1.9 million employees)1.5 million of whom work for franchises.

Roles and Responsibilities:

In this AMC Project I have migrated the current McDonald's site deployed on AEM 5.6 to Adobe Marketing Cloud on AEM 6.1.

Independently identify, Analysis and replicate customer's problems and then escalate complex problem according to defined escalation procedures.

Process warranty and replacement requests for products.

Retain ownership of all cases throughout the resolution process.

Environment: Adobe Enterprises Manager (AEM Tool), Java 5, CQ5, Maven, Web logic, jsp

Client

Debenhams (Debenhams-UK)

Role

Senior Software Engineer

Duration

June'2013-June'2017

Project Type

Implementation & Support

Debenhams plc is a British multinational retailer operating under a department Store format in the United Kingdom and Ireland with franchise stores in other countries. The company was founded in the eighteenth century as a single store in London and has now grown to 172 locations across the UK, Ireland and Denmark. It sells a range of clothing, household items and furniture and has been known since 1993 for its 'Designers at Debenhams' brand range.

Debenhams has implemented Sterling Commerce 8 (Yantra) as their order management system and they keep on enhancing their business by including various projects that require configuration/customization of Sterling DOM.

The yantra Multi Channel Order Management solution from Sterling Commerce, a multi-enterprise collaboration company, has been selected by Debenhams, a UK department store chain. The solution is reportedly based on Sterling's Multi Enterprise Services Architecture (MESA) and composite applications are said to work with the existing IT infrastructure. According to Sterling, Yantra offers flexibility and visibility into value chain operations and the solution can be adapted to suit changes in business needs or partnerships.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Configuration changes in Sterling DOM to include new functionality or modify existing.
- Debugging and Customizing Sterling DOM to improve/include the functionality using Java coding.
- Contacting clients directly for any clarification on requirements.
- Analysis to find out the root cause of any exception.
- Resolving high priority tickets.
- Tracking, Logging & Reporting using SALSA.
- Involved in fixing issues and bugs.

Environment: Java 5, Oracle Express Edition, Sterling (yantra)8.0, Sql Developer, Eclipse, Web logic Bea, XML, XSL

Client

Reliance 4G Portals (Payment Gateway-Product Development). Reliance India

Role

Software Engineer

Duration

Aug'2012-April2013

Project Type

Development

Transaction through Web Service through spring in Maven-project payment gateway for Reliance 4G Service and Bill desk integration for payment. Major roles are creating Registration for R4G customers, Prepaid Customers and Merchant and their transaction through different mode. Migrated Project in to Magnolia CMS.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Coding, Development and Business Logic Generation, Client Side Support and Bill Desk Integration.

Client Side validation using Ajax and Js, JQuery.

Wallet Creation, Setting Payment Configuration.

Mode of Payment through Mobile or POS Device.

NFC enables future Payment with No-Click and One Click Options.

Converting jsp files in to Magnolia jsp files using Magnolia CMS (Content Management System).

Environment: Windows, Javal.5, Jboss 9.1, MySQL, Spring 3.0, Hibernate, Magnolia CMS, Net Beans (JDBC, Servlets, JSP, XML)

Training

Organization

Training

HCL Technologies

Trained in ATG

Trained in Adobe CQ5

Trained in Sterling OMS

Organization

Training

Kanha Tech

Solutions

Oracle

Application Server

Trained in Financial, Banking, Insurance Domain